My name is Echidna...
Or perhaps you would know me
better as the Witch of Greed?
Please, it hurts to see you
look so alarmed by me.
Despite who I am, I'm still a
tender young maiden, you know.
Sorry, but...
There's no way I'm not going to
be alarmed when you tell me
you're the Witch of Greed the moment we meet.
I see.
That's a fair point.
What is this place?
I was in some dark ruins just a moment ago!
When did you move me?!
Unfortunately, you're mistaken.
You weren't physically moved anywhere.
You were merely invited to my tea party.
Tea party?
A witch's tea party.
Are you going to stand there forever?
Why don't you at least sit down
before the tea gets cold?
Oh, damn it!
All right, fine!
You're awfully brave,
gulping down tea served by a witch in one gulp.
Hah! If you really wanted to kill me,
I'd be a pile of ash the very next instant.
What's this tea, anyway? It's not bad,
but it's not good, either.
It's something that's produced here.
To put it bluntly,
it's a body fluid of mine.
What the hell did you just make me drink?!
You truly are a fascinating individual.
You're standing right here in
front of me as if it's normal.
Hah! You think you're so pretty that a
normal person's eyes would fall out?
I'll have you know that my eyes are blessed
throughout the day by the prettiest girl alive!
So no matter how many times I look at you,
I'm not going to see you as particularly pretty.
No, most normal people vomit
when they stand before me.
Funny, right?
There's nothing funny about that!
What is it you want with me?
Nothing, really.
You came in here of your own accord.
If you want to go back, I'll send you back...
But are you sure that's what you want?
Huh?
An opportunity to talk to the Witch of Greed
is not something that just anyone,
other than you, can earn.
The only requirement to have a dialogue
is for both of us to exist.
Let's remove everything
unnecessary from the picture.
All we need is our words.
Let me affirm all the desires,
the curiosities, the greed,
that you seek to satisfy with answers.
Now, what would you like to ask me?
About the Witch of Gluttony, Daphne,
who created beasts that defied the will
of God to save the world from starvation?
About the Witch of Lust, Carmilla,
who granted emotions to non-human beings
in an attempt to fill the world with love?
About the Witch of Wrath, Minerva,
who struck people to heal them as she
lamented the state of her war-torn world?
About the Witch of Sloth, Sekhmet,
who drove a dragon past the
great waterfall just for a chance to rest?
About the Witch of Pride, Typhon,
who, out of youthful innocence and cruelty,
judged criminals one after another?
About the Witch of Greed, Echidna,
the embodiment of the thirst for knowledge,
who has done things she regrets
even in the realm of death, all in
pursuit of all types of knowledge?
Or...
The Witch of Envy, who killed
all the other witches
and used them as sustenance while she
made the whole world her enemy—
the most detestable of them all?
Oh, darn.
It looks like I've frightened you too much.
Such is the nature of a witch.
It's quite bothersome.
Oh, that took less time than I thought.
People who are compatible
really do adapt quickly.
What are you saying?
That tea you drank?
I used the Sloth Witch Factor on
it to strengthen your resistance.
Now you and I can talk at leisure.
So... what would you like to ask me?
You won't get away with this!
What did you do to my body?!
Please don't get the wrong idea.
I didn't make you drink that tea with
the intention of doing anything bad.
In fact, I find your existence
quite desirable.
I'm a bit embarrassed, really.
Huh?
In these past few days, you killed the one
who possessed the Sloth Witch Factor, correct?
When he died, the Witch Factor
chose you as its new dwelling.
That's also why you were able to
enter this graveyard unharmed.
Graveyard? Like... a tomb?
Yes.
This is the Witch's Graveyard,
where my soul is held prisoner...
The Sanctuary.
You know where the Sanctuary is?!
I don't have the experience
to determine whether
you're brave or just very bold...
Don't make fun of me!
So can I consider this... rather, the forest
with the ruins where I was before...
to be the Sanctuary?
You're so mean...
That's right. Just as you wanted,
the Sanctuary is outside the ruins.
So, what else would you like to as—
And if I ask you, you'll let me back out, right?
Sure... I can guarantee that.
Hey, isn't there anything
you want to ask me?
Sorry, but I'd rather meet up with
Emilia outside than talk to you.
Huh?
Y-You're kidding, right?!
I'm the Witch of Greed!
Powerful people from around the world have
come to me in search of my knowledge!
So, um... relax, okay?!
We can just relax and talk!
I have knowledge about the truth
of this world that nobody—
Not interested.
What?!
I'll make time to chat over
tea with you later, okay?
You'd ask a dead woman...
a witch, at that...
to agree to that as if it
were the simplest thing?
I've never had a tea party like this.
If you're really going back,
I'll just take my compensation first.
J-Just so you know, I'm broke beyond compare...
Compensation for a witch doesn't mean money.
What I desire from you is a vow.
You will tell no one of what has
transpired at this tea party.
That is my condition.
And, since you're here,
I'll send you away with a souvenir.
I will grant you the right to
face the trial of the Sanctuary.
The trial of the Sanctuary?
You may not understand now,
but once you learn where it is,
you will realize its worth.
What feelings will you have
toward me when that happens?
The mere thought gives me
such beautiful expectations.
You... really are a witch, aren't you?
Yes, that's right.
I'm a very, very evil magic user.
Anyway, I need to get out of here,
and back to Emilia-tan and Otto.
I feel like...
someone said something to me.
Otto?!
Look at you, just waltzing out of there!
You've got some nerve, outsider!
Is this like a magmarin laughing
when it's full of holes?!
Ow...
Damn it! What the hell?
What a tantalizing choice!
That's a nice ground dragon ya got there.
Wait, Patrasche!
You're a real good-lookin' girl, ain't ya?
I'm not gonna hurt ya!
Just take a little nap!
Better thank her for fightin' so hard for ya!
Wait... Wait!
I'm gonna throw you guys outta
this forest half-dead...
Just alive enough to swear you won't
tell a soul about this place!
You know Frederica, don't you?!
Why the hell did I just hear that
name from your nasty mouth?
Why do you think?
Just think about it!
Thought about it. Don't know.
I'll think after I bash your skull in!
Quit jumping to conclusions without thinking!
It's because we know her, too!
Huh?
I'm Garfiel.
If you guys know her, you must've
heard that name, right?
Y-You're...
How the hell did you know I have
anything to do with Frederica?!
Are you being serious right now?
I just got beaten up for nothing.
What am I supposed to do with this anger?
You never shut up, do ya, trader?
I apologized, didn't I?
You call, "Hey, sorry, numbskull,
I kinda jumped the gun," an apology?!
Anyway, if you'd shown me that
thing sooner, that woulda done it.
Gotta act on a ganglion
before ya think about it.
Gangli... huh?
Lookin' at that hair, I'm guessin'
that's the famous Emilia-sama?
The silver-haired half-devil
that Roswaal's helpin' out.
She's a half-elf!
Don't you ever call her that again!
Hey, look at that! Guess you can put
some energy into yer voice after all!
Wanna know how it feels to be a
bazomazo bein' flung back an' forth?
Uh, is there some sort of translation
glitch happening between you and me?
Huh?
Emilia!
I'm so glad you're okay!
Subaru?
Who are you?!
Just so you know, I won't let
you lay a finger on Subaru!
Hang on, Emilia-tan!
I appreciate it, but as a guy, I have
mixed feelings about this! Really, I'm fine!
I'm not gonna do anything.
I don't want Ram givin' me hell later.
Ram?
This is Garfiel.
Garfiel... The one Frederica told us about?
Yeah, and he's showing us the
way to the Sanctuary now.
Ram and the villagers from
Arlam are there... right?
Don't wanna believe me? That's your call.
Ain't no turnin' back now, though.
We're already past the barrier.
Then we're in the Sanctuary right now?
C'mon, gimme a break.
Weren't you asleep 'cause you
got close to the barrier?
The barrier?
Come to think of it, when the stone glowed...
It was at the exact same moment.
So it was reacting to the barrier, then?
But why did only Emilia-tan pass out?
I mean, I got transported somewhere, but Otto—
You know damn well why the barrier
reacted to her and not you two.
It's not just half-elves that thing reacts to.
It works on me and a lot of others, too.
That's 'cause...
Because you have mixed blood, too?
So the Sanctuary is a place where
demihumans with mixed blood live?
You guessed it!
We welcome you, Emilia-sama,
and your two escorts, too!
Roswaal likes to go around
callin' it the Sanctuary,
but it ain't the kinda place
that deserves such a nice name.
Nothin' there but a hodgepodge of halfwits.
It's just a dead-end testing ground.
Um, where should...
You're back?
It took you long enough.
Ram!
I haven't a clue which Barusu you are,
but I'm disappointed by how
long it took you to get here.
Ah, but I suppose I was a
fool to expect more of you.
If your story is that you "haven't
a clue" who I am, stick to it!
Hmph.
Emilia-sama, I welcome you.
Roswaal-sama is waiting inside.
Allow me to show you the way.
Garf, take the ground dragon and
carriage somewhere suitable.
Is that any way to treat me?
That's just how I like it, though.
Yo, cabbie, follow me.
Are you referring to me?!
That's the worst name you've called me yet!
Also, I have to be alone with you?!
I'll pick up what's left of you.
Why am I being treated so roughly?!
What're you talking about?
When I was unconscious,
Emilia only stayed safe because you were there.
I'm grateful.
O-Oh?
W-Well, as long as you're appreciative...
Right!
He's too easy.
What?
Oh, just... wondering how you were doing.
You remember what was going
on the last time I saw you.
I couldn't get in touch with you after that,
and to be honest, I was really worried.
As you can see, I am as
lovely and healthy as ever.
The villagers of Arlam are all safe, too.
You can be at ease.
I see...
Yeah, that's... a real relief.
A real relief.
U-Um, listen...
Hey, Ram...
This really isn't a place
to stand around and talk.
Would you show us inside?
Certainly.
Subaru, are you all right?
Yeah.
I'm sorry for interrupting you, but...
No, I get it.
I just freaked out a little.
For her to not even ask about Rem
when all this is going on...
I'm pathetic, huh?
It's only natural to be scared.
I'll never think that's pathetic.
Let's go.
We'll fix what happened to Rem,
and everything else, too.
Got it.
No matter what happens,
I'll be your meat shield and keep you safe.
Ah, Emilia-sama and Subaru-kun.
It feels like it's been so very
long since I last saw you.
I was going to slug you when
I saw you again, but now...
What the heck happened?
What could have hurt you so badly?
Well, now, where shall I begin?
Hey, before that, just one thing...
The alliance with Crusch-san is on.
Now are you satisfied with the
results you got from abandoning me?
Yes, most satisfied.
Truly, truly,
you were the once-in-a-lifetime
windfall I had long waited for.
Oh, really?
Roswaal, what is this place?
Since we got here... no, since we
made contact with the barrier...
I've had this anxious feeling
in my chest, and I can't relax.
I've heard it called the "Sanctuary,"
but it doesn't seem like one to me at all.
In fact, it feels more like...
The Witch's Graveyard?
Does it seem to make far
more sense to call it that?
What do you mean?
Exactly what I said, nothing more or less.
This is where the Witch of Greed,
Echidna, met her end long ago,
and in my mind, it is worth
calling a "Sanctuary."
Echidna...
Subaru?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
And why are you overseeing a place
with that kind of backstory?
It's quite simple.
This land has been overseen by the heads
of the Mathers family for generations.
Then the Mathers family and
the Witch of Greed have—
Echidna.
Huh?
Please, when you speak
of her, do use her name.
The name "Witch of Greed"
makes her sound so evil.
That's not very nice, is it?
Um, then... The Mathers family and Echidna
have been acquainted for a long time,
and that's why they've always
overseen this place?
Yes, though to say we "oversee"
it is a bit of an exaggeration.
Echidna's barrier prevents entry
by outsiders who fail to follow
the forest's proper procedure.
In addition, the barrier has
certain effects on those
whose blood meets certain conditions.
Did you not experience this
yourself, Emilia-sama?
And how did you end up in such a sorry state?
Did you not find it at all strange, Emilia-sama?
Huh?
That all the people who fled to the Sanctuary,
as well as Roswaal-sama
and myself, stayed here
and didn't return to the mansion?
Well...
I mean, you stayed here
because you're hurt, right?
We are all being held under house
arrest here in the Sanctuary.
Huh?!
Myself, Ram, and the people of Arlam...
Oh, and you two as well, from the
moment you entered here.
The hell? You guys are still
flappin' your gums in here?
House arrest... Then are Roswaal's injuries...
Nope. He got hurt 'cause he
was rejected by the trial.
Trial?
What does that mean?
You've seen what happens when you come
in contact with the barrier, right?
Mixed-bloods who go through
that and still come in here
are never allowed to leave.
Does that mean Emilia, too?
The barrier doesn't mean squat to most people.
Doesn't that seem a little unfair, Emilia-sama?
The only way to break the barrier is
to go through the graveyard's trial,
but if anyone who isn't a
mixed-blood tries it...
All the villagers are rounded up in one place.
So long as they don't act up, we won't hurt 'em.
They even get three meals
and a nap every day!
This is our demand.
Break the barrier surrounding
this Sanctuary.
The only one allowed to undergo
the trial to do that is you.
If you can't break it, we won't
let any of the villagers leave.
Of course, you can't leave
here yourself, either!
Subaru-sama!
Thank goodness you're safe!
I'm glad you're all okay.
Are the others all right?
Is the lord recovering from his injuries?
We heard he got hurt trying to help us.
We're truly relieved!
Okay, everyone, listen up.
As you know, we got rid of the bad
guy who attacked the village.
The other group that evacuated
is back at the village, waiting for
all of you to come home.
I guess you've all been informed that
it's not easy to get out of here.
But don't worry!
We've got someone who's going to undergo
the trial to set you all free!
You mean...
You're going to do it?
No, if I could do it, I'd be
more than happy to, but...
I think you all know who this is.
It's Emilia, the royal selection candidate.
She'll be undergoing the trial.
I-I'm sorry you had to wait so long.
In the place of your domain lord,
Roswaal L. Mathers,
I will undergo the trial.
I would appreciate your support!
Let me ask you just one thing.
Chief...
Why do this?
You bowed your head to us the
last time you saw us, too,
but we were the ones who turned you away.
If it's because you want us to
back you in the royal selection,
that's just fine, so long
as you come out and say so.
But if you have some other reason,
we would like to know...
that you are not a witch who
is beyond our comprehension.
I don't have the confidence to give
you a respectable answer right now.
I don't have any strong, convincing
words that would satisfy all of you.
But...
Though it wasn't for very long,
I spent a few days with your families,
the ones who aren't here now.
And it made me realize...
that families should be together.
I want to return all of you to your families.
I didn't promise them that I'd do so...
But I promised myself.
That's my only reason.
I wasn't really thinking about
earning your support or anything.
But if possible, I'd like to...
um...
be friends with you all.
That's what I want.
Emilia-sama...
Y-Yes?
I realize this will sound like we
only care about what benefits us,
but...
I pray you will accept our friendship.
P-Please, I should ask the same!
I know I'm not worthy,
but please accept my friendship!
"I'm not worthy"? Who says
that in this day and age?
Emilia-sama...
seems to have changed a bit.
Is it because of something you said to her?
It's the result of her thinking
things through on her own.
You shouldn't assume all her
decisions come from someone else.
You're right.
I was in the wrong this time.
Did you get enough support
from the lesser spirits?
Yeah. Everything's fine.
Still, I think I'd like one last cheer.
Can I do it?
I want you to.
Please.
You can do it! Don't give up! EMC!
Emilia-tan, major challenger!
Thank you.
That means she's been approved as a
qualified challenger in the trial.
I'm going now.
I get that it sucks being trapped here.
But why didn't you do this yourself?
If I could, I would, damn it.
H-Hey, is she gonna be okay?
The light's not supposed to go out
as long as the trial's going on...
Emilia!
Barusu!
Why...
I don't understand, but if I can get
in there, that's good enough for me!
Just stay there! I'll yell if I need you!
Emilia!
First, you need to face your own past.
Good morning, son of mine!
Hey, c'mon! What? What? What's wrong?
You look as if you just saw your own
dad naked first thing in the morning!
The Long-Awaited Reunion